Privacy Policy

nib holdings limited ABN 51 125 633 856 and all relatedentities within the nib Group (“nib Group”) or (“nib”)

Dated 1 July 2024

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 2 of 13

Contents

1. Collecting your personal information ..................................................................................... 31.1. The types of information we may collect ........................................................................ 31.2. Who we collect this information from ............................................................................. 41.3. Insurance policies with more than one insured person or purchased on behalf ofanother person ......................................................................................................................... 51.4. If you do not provide us with your personal information ..................................................... 52. Using your personal information ........................................................................................... 62.1. How nib uses your personal information ........................................................................ 62.2. Legal basis for using your information............................................................................ 72.3. Direct Marketing and personalisation ............................................................................. 83. Storing and disclosing your personal information .................................................................. 83.1. Who we disclose your personal information to ............................................................... 93.2. We may disclose your personal information overseas ................................................. 105. Accessing and correcting your personal information ........................................................... 115.1. nib Group..................................................................................................................... 115.2. European Economic Area (EEA) and United Kingdom................................................. 125.3. nib Securities ............................................................................................................... 13

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 3 of 13

nib Group and Privacy

This information explains how we comply with applicable privacy requirements and setsout minimum standards for how we deal with personal information collected and usedby the nib Group to maintain individual privacy, including maintaining confidentiality andensuring security. We may occasionally update this information. You should read this inconjunction with any specific privacy policies for our different businesses and locations,available on their websites, or in privacy notices provided to you based on yourrelationship with us.In this Privacy Policy, “we, our, us or nib Group” means nib holdings limited, ABN 51125 633 856 and its related entities in the nib Group of companies in Australia andother countries including, in the case of the European Economic Area (EEA), nib TravelServices Europe Limited and nib Travel Services Ireland Limited, and in the UK, nibTravel Services Europe (UK Branch).nib Group’s system for complying with applicable privacy requirements includes:

• our commitment to be responsible with your information and treat it with care;

• our adherence with privacy requirements, including privacy laws, contractualagreements, and our policies and standards;

• our resources allocated to privacy and data protection, including ourtechnology systems and services;

• our procedures to prevent and respond to any data breach; and

• our people and the training and education we undertake.In the event of any conflict between the English language version of this Privacy Policyand other language versions, the English language version will prevail.

1. Collecting your personal information

The businesses operated by the nib Group of companies provide a range of services,including health, life and travel insurance, support coordination and National DisabilityInsurance Scheme (NDIS) plan management services, and provide information inrelation to health care and health care providers, disability services and other services.

1.1.The types of information we may collect

The types of personal information we collect will depend on your relationship with us,such as whether you are a nib Group customer, website or app user, job applicant,employee (in applicable jurisdictions), a claimant, a health service provider or anotherthird party (such as a financial adviser or an existing or potential business partner). Ifyou are a nib Group customer, the types of personal information we collect will furtherdepend on the type of product or service (including the type of policy) we provide toyou.

When you deal with us, we may collect personal information about or relating to yousuch as:(a) your name, contact details, gender and other information about yourcircumstances and preferences including about your health or medical history,health related information such as your diet and lifestyle, financial information(such as your salary for certain life insurance products), government relatedidentifiers, residency, travel visa and employment details, employment andincome information, professional accreditations, bank account and credit carddetails, information about your use of our products, services, websites andmobile applications, and in some cases, your biometric information (such asyour voiceprint or fingerprint);

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 4 of 13

(b) where disability services are applicable, information such as details of yourdisability, physical or mental health and support requirements, identificationnumbers associated with you, details of your guardian/nominee or supportcoordinator including names, addresses and contact details; details of yournominated service providers and bank account details for payment of invoices.For more detailed information on how we manage personal information relatedto disability services provided through our nib Thrive business, please refer tothe nib Thrive Privacy Policy;(c) if you hold nib securities, information relating to you and your security holding;and(d) details about your interactions with us, like phone calls and emails, as well asinformation about your use of our website or applications using cookies or otherdigital tracking technology.

1.2.Who we collect this information from

We collect this information when we ask you for it and you provide it, including whenyou visit our website or social media pages, become one of our representatives orbusiness partners, apply to receive products or services from us, use our productsand services, when an insurance claim is lodged by you or on your behalf, or whereapplicable, from employees or prospective employees. We may also collectinformation about you from third parties, such as your insurer for travel insurance,doctor, treating hospital or other health service provider, or recruitment agency, if it isnot reasonable or practicable to collect the information from you, or where youprovide your consent for us to do so. This may also include other people ororganisations who might be representing you (such as your next of kin, nominatedrepresentative, legal guardian or power of attorney), including a person who takes outan insurance policy on your behalf (ie your employer) or under which you arecovered, or any person assisting or representing us, including any recruitment orvetting agencies.We may also collect your personal information from third parties who provide servicesto nib, including emergency assistance services to travel insurance customers,predicted health outcomes based on identified health, lifestyle and demographicfactors, as well as publicly available sources such as internet search engines or socialnetworking services. When we do so, we ensure that we have a legal basis for usingyour personal information, such as to enable us to contact you and offer our productsand services to you. We may also collect personal information about others such asparents and guardians, carers or authorised representatives of third parties.If you are a recognised health care provider, we may collect your personal informationfrom databases and directories to support our business processes, including to ensureclaims are dealt with efficiently, to investigate complaints or to conduct fraud-preventionchecks.Like many companies, we use technology and tools that tell us when a computer ordevice has visited or accessed our content, including information such as serveraddress or IP address. Those tools include services from search engines and othercompanies that help us to tailor our products and services to better suit our customersand potential customers. Search engines provide facilities to allow you to indicateyour preferences in relation to the use of those tools in connection with computersand other devices controlled or used by you. Our mobile applications may also collectprecise location information from your device if you consent to the collection of thisinformation, and we will always respect your preferences including if you choose towithdraw your consent at any time.

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 5 of 13

1.3.Insurance policies with more than one insured person or purchased on behalfof another person

If you have a Couples or Family health insurance policy with us, or hold a policy thathas been taken out on your behalf, we may collect your information from thepolicyholder or person or employer who took out the policy on your behalf. Thepolicyholder will also have access to all the information on the policy, including thoseof their partner and any dependants.

If you have a travel insurance policy that names more than one adult on yourCertificate of Insurance, or where your policy has been taken out by another person onyour behalf, we may collect information from them about you.If you have a life insurance policy that has been taken out by another person (i.e. youremployer) on your behalf, we may collect information from them about you.As a policyholder or person providing information about a member or person, weexpect, and will reasonably assume, that:

• you have obtained their consent to give nib their personal information, and forus to use that information as set out in this privacy policy and as otherwisepermitted by law;

• you have told them you have provided their personal information to nib;

• you have made them aware of the information set out in this privacy policy andinformed them of how they can access nib’s privacy policy; and

• you have told them they are entitled to access their information by contactingus.

For health insurance, if a policyholder lodges a claim on your behalf, or for travelinsurance, if a co-insured adult lodges a claim on your behalf, we act in reliance onthe above representations given by that person. Unless you tell us otherwise when wenotify you of the claim lodgement, we assume you have given your consent to thepolicyholder or co-insured to provide all the information we need to process yourclaim.

In relation to disability services we provide that may involve authorisedrepresentatives, such as if a family member or support coordinator acts on yourbehalf, we rely on representations made on your behalf. If you ask us to assist withmanagement in relation to these services, we will ask you to provide your consent toshare your personal information with third parties.

For life insurance, if a beneficiary of your policy (or their representative) lodges aclaim on your behalf, we act in reliance on the above representations given by thatperson.

1.4. If you do not provide us with your personal information

You may choose not to provide us with your personal information. There are somecircumstances where you can deal with us anonymously or use a pseudonym, such asif you are seeking general information about our products or services rather than acustomised individual quote. Where we do not have your personal information (orpersonal information of an insured person, a participant of special services, a personrequesting assistance or accessing products/services), or if you have withdrawnconsent (when consent is the primary legal basis for handling your information), wemay not be able to contact you, process your requests or employment application, orprovide our services to you including providing insurance or other assistance,

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 6 of 13

processing an insurance claim or pay invoices.

2. Using your personal information

2.1. How nib uses your personal information

Generally, we use your personal information for our business and activities, and in ourefforts to expand and improve our business. Examples include:

• to identify you, and respond to and process your requests for information andprovide you with a product or service;

• to determine your eligibility to provide or receive a nib Group health or relatedproduct or service, or a travel insurance service, including to determine anyexisting medical conditions, and to manage our relationship with you includingwhere relevant, providing you with a quote or managing insurance related andother services being provided by or to you;

• to administer and provide insurance services, including health managementprogrammes, emergency assistance, and to manage your and our rights andobligations (and those of insured persons) in relation to insurance services,including dealing with you or an insured person in connection with aninsurance proposal, policy, or claim;

• to provide support coordination and NDIS plan management in relation todisability services, including payment of invoices;

• to recommend updates to insurance policies to ensure adequate coverage forservices beneficial to you;

• to administer promotional programmes and scholarships, such as exclusivemember offers, competitions or university research scholarships sponsored bynib, when you have provided consent as part of your application;

• to conduct business processing functions including providing personalinformation to our related bodies corporate, contractors, service providers,underwriting partners or other third parties including those making referralsto us and to our strategic, distribution and “white label partners” who marketand sell our products and services to their customers under their own brand;

• to prepare internal reports and conduct market research for the purposes ofimproving our products, services and internal operations, including to improveour online services, manage our servers and websites, and to collect andanalyse statistical information;

• to provide you with advice or information relating to your policy or needs, includinginsurance needs;

• to manage complaints and disputes, and report to dispute resolution bodies;

• to operate programs and forums in different media in which you are able to shareinformation, including your personal information, with us and publicly (on theterms applicable);

• to manage, train and develop our employees and representatives;

• for a business or professional relationship we may have with you;

• if you apply for employment with us, to consider your application;

• to carry out credit checks, credit reporting and other background checks; for debtrecovery purposes;

• where you are a health service provider or emergency assistance

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 7 of 13

provider, to manage our relationship with you and your relationship withour members, which may include engaging agents to perform thisfunction on nib’s behalf. Other ways nib may use personal information ofhealth service providers includes for billing purposes, investigating andresolving member or regulator enquiries and complaints, and creatingand providing access to directory services and costs information tomembers and other third parties;

• to undertake data analytics, including in relation to de-identified data;

• to provide services linked with telehealth services offered by nib so that ourmembers can enjoy video or phone consultations with healthcare professionals;

• to provide services utilising voice commands or recordings to assist nib membersto assess nib’s products or services such as locating healthcare professionalsusing voice commands, or where you have given consent to assist to verify youridentity (such as nib’s voice-based bot);

• to comply with our legal obligations, and to detect and prevent fraudulent activity inour business;

• to assist Government Departments in the delivery of national schemes, such asthe Pacific Australia Labour Mobility (PALM) Scheme and the National DisabilityInsurance Scheme (NDIS);

• to amend records to remove personal information;

• to improve the contents of, and the services we provide through, our websites andmobile applications; and

• for other everyday business purposes that involve use of personal information.The above examples are a non-exhaustive overview only of how we may collect anduse your personal information, and more detail may be provided to you in a separateprivacy notice when you contact us or, where relevant, in a separate contractualarrangement with you.

2.2.Legal basis for using your information

We ensure that we have an appropriate legal basis to deal with your personalinformation in these ways, including:

• where you have provided your consent (such as when you provide your consentto receive marketing messages);

• where it is necessary for us to use your personal information in order to enter intoor perform a contract (such as to send you a Product Disclosure Statement andQuotation in response to your product inquiry, to provide you with disabilityservices under a signed agreement with you, or if we need to handle aninsurance claim), or to protect your vital interests (such as to provide emergencymedical assistance under a travel insurance policy you hold with us);

• where the applicable law permits us or requires us, including when we have alegal or regulatory obligation that we must comply with or is in the substantialpublic interest (such as to prevent fraud or money laundering) or we need touse your personal information to establish, exercise or defend legal rights (suchas debt recovery) or whenever courts are acting in their judicial capacity; and

• where we need to use your personal information for our legitimate businessinterests (such as managing our business operations, developing and improvingthe products and services we offer, company re-structure or selling part of ourbusiness), and when we do so, we will consider your rights and interests inaccordance with applicable law.

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 8 of 13

2.3.Direct Marketing and personalisation

Generally, we use your personal information for our business and activities, and in ourefforts to improve our offerings to you. Examples include:

• to offer and provide personalised health information, support and services;

• to offer and invite you to health management programs;

• to provide you with marketing communications and invitations and offers forproducts and services including new products or services that we or our thirdparty business partners believe may be of interest to you and to assist indeveloping new products and services; and

• to provide improved services to you through our website, social media channelsand to develop and improve the products and services we offer to you and/or toour customers;

If we use your personal information to contact you and you would prefer us not to, or ifyou indicate a preference for a method of communication, please let us know and wewill respect your preference. Please contact nib using the contact information at theend of this policy or via the method below:

• Australian Residents Health Insurance

my.nib.com.au/login

• New Zealand Residents – Life and Health Insurance

health.nib.co.nz/contact-us

• nib Travel Insurance

www.nibtravelinsurance.com.au/contact

• Iman Australia Health Plans

and International Workers \& Students

my.nib.com.au/login

• World Nomads

pp.worldnomads.com/contact-us

• Travel Insurance Direct

www.travelinsurancedirect.com.au/customer-contact

• nib Thrive

https://www.nib.com.au/thrive/contact-us

• OrbitProtect

https://orbitprotect.com/contact-us/When your choice is to continue to deal with us and in circumstances where youhave been provided a functional unsubscribe facility and have not unsubscribed,we take it that you agree to and consent to us using your personal information,providing we follow the approach we explain in this Privacy Policy and comply withthe law.

3. Storing and disclosing your personal information

Personal information is retained during the time we need it for the identified purposes,

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 9 of 13

to the extent necessary for purposes reasonably related to those identified purposes(for example, resolving disputes) or as required by law.

3.1.Who we disclose your personal information to

In using and storing your personal information, we may pass on your personalinformation, including outside the country of collection:

• to third parties, like our consultants, agents, contractors and serviceproviders, and those that act as data controllers, processors or analysts,information technology providers, auditors or external advisers;

• to others who may be involved in your care, or in respect of disability services, theprovision of support to you;

• to any intermediaries, including your agent, adviser, broker, representative orperson acting on your behalf;

• to your employer or group administrator, if you are an international workersmember (such as an IMAN member or if you are part of the PALM scheme) ormember of a workplace or association insurance plan, in order to administerthat plan or where determined necessary or reasonable to do so, including inconnection with any suspected unlawful activity associated with your insurancecover;

• to other insurers, reinsurers, insurance investigators and claims or insurancereference services, brokers, loss assessors, financiers;

• if you hold a travel insurance policy with us, to banks, foreign currency providers,goods replacement suppliers, transport and accommodation providers, travelagents and consultants, medical or health service providers or practitioners,emergency assistance providers, security providers, witnesses, translators or anyother third parties involved in the processing, investigation or settling of a claim;

• if you are an authorised representative or a supplier of the nib Group, tocredit providers or credit reporting agencies;

• to other companies in the nib Group, including those located in Australia, NewZealand, the Republic of Ireland, United Kingdom, the United States, thePhilippines, Brazil and the Cayman Islands;

• to any of our nib Group strategic, distribution and whitelabel partners whereauthorised or required;

• where relevant, to a potential or actual third party purchaser of our businessor assets;

• where relevant, to local registration boards and professional and industry bodiesand associations, or to external dispute resolution bodies or other third partiesinvolved in the management and resolution of complaints;

• to debt collection agencies and other parties that assist with debt recovery;

• for legal or safety reasons or other special circumstances, such as in orderto comply with a legal or regulatory obligation to protect your vital interests;

• where we have a legitimate purpose (such as to manage our businessoperations or to conduct data analytics to improve our offerings);

• to any person authorised by you, or to others you have nominated, to accessinformation in connection with an insurance policy you hold with us;

• to other persons who are insured on your policy to confirm, for example, that fulldisclosure has been made to us, or to ensure that the policyholder or personmanaging a claim has details of claims made on the policy, including any

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 10 of 13

personal information used to make a claim determination; and

• in additional ways the applicable law permits us, or that you may also agree to.We may also disclose to third parties information from which information directlyidentifying individuals has been removed (such as aggregated, anonymous orpseudonymised information) so that your identity is not ascertainable. This includessharing data analytics results.

3.2.We may disclose your personal information overseas

When we pass on, transfer or share your personal information in this way, we takesteps to ensure it is treated in the same way that we would treat it, and that anadequate level of protection is in place in accordance with relevant privacy and dataprotection laws.For example, if your personal information is collected in the EEA (European EconomicArea) and we (or third parties acting on our behalf) transfer personal information thatwe collect about you to countries outside of the EEA (such as when we need to collector share this information with nib’s parent company located in Australia), your personalinformation may be subject to both Australian and European privacy requirements, andthe steps that we take to protect your personal information include obtaining contractualcommitments to comply with applicable privacy requirements (referred to underEuropean data protection laws as “Standard Contractual Clauses”). If we transferpersonal information from inside the UK to third countries outside the UK which havenot been certified by the UK as having an adequate level of protection, steps we take toprotect your personal information may include having an International Data TransferAgreement in place, or using “Standard Contractual Clauses” with UK addendum.Depending on the circumstances of the particular transfer, other steps we might takeinclude transferring personal information to companies in the United States which arecertified under the “Privacy Shield” (in the case of EU-US transfers of personal data).Where you are covered by one of our Australian international students or visitors’health insurance policies, we may disclose your personal information to overseasrecipients who will generally be located in your original country of residence from whereyou are departing to Australia. This ensures that your health insurance coverage meetsboth the requirements of your visa and your health insurance needs while you are inAustralia.Some businesses within the nib Group (e.g., our travel insurance businesses) haverelationships with insurers and other entities overseas. The countries in which theserecipients may be located will vary from time to time, but may include the UnitedKingdom, the United States, Canada, Malta, Denmark, and Brazil. In addition, somebusinesses in the nib Group may have relationships with overseas service providers(including in China) to help manage information technology needs. The types ofinformation we disclose depends on your relationship with us and may includeidentifiable information associated with your insurance policy or other services you'veengaged with, including claims and health information.We may also disclose your personal information to health service providers and otherswe have business arrangements with overseas as necessary to enable them to offertheir products and services to you, such as where you are covered by a travelinsurance policy and require appropriate medical treatment and services whileoverseas (and if we do so, we will ensure we meet applicable data protectionrequirements, such as explicit consent, or protection of the vital interests of a datasubject). We do our best to keep our records of your personal information up to dateand accurate, and to delete or amend personal information that is no longer needed.

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 11 of 13

4. How we protect your information

We use various systems and services including technical measures to safeguard thepersonal information we store, as part of our business systems and processes. Wetake steps to protect your personal information from misuse, interference or loss andunauthorised access, modification and disclosure with appropriate safeguards andsecurity measures. This includes in storage and when we transfer or share it, such asacross borders, to ensure compliance with international data protection standardsrelevant to our travel, overseas student and worker health insurance policies.

All our staff are trained to understand privacy and data protection requirements. Wealso conduct Privacy Impact Assessments on new systems and processes, to ensurewe are adhering with privacy requirements and putting the right protections in placewhen making changes. We have teams and programmes in place to check ourprotections are working and remain up to date, including our protections to prevent anddetect cyber threats. We are regularly audited to provide an independent assessmentof our protection measures and help us to continue to maintain standards of personalinformation management and protection.While we take steps to protect your personal information when you send it to us, youshould keep in mind that no internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free. If you provide any personal information to us via our online services (includingemail or a web-based service through a portal), or if we provide information to you orothers by these means, the privacy, security and integrity of any data transfer over theinternet cannot be guaranteed. When you share information with us (such as over theinternet, or sending us an email), it is at your own risk as factors beyond our controlinclude the security of the device and/or program you use to communicate with us, andsteps you take to protect your login details and password. If you reasonably believe thatthere has been unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal information, pleasecontact us (see below).Our website may contain links or references to other websites or social mediaplatforms not subject to this Privacy Policy. You should check their own privacypolicies before providing your personal information.

5. Accessing and correcting your personal information

5.1. nib Group

You may wish to contact nib Group to access your personal information, to seek tocorrect it, delete it, to make a complaint about privacy (and under applicable privacylaws you may have rights of access to and correction of your personal information) or tomanage your communication preferences. Our privacy email contact address for ourGroup Privacy Officer is privacyofficer@nib.com.au and further contact details for nibGroup are set out below.nib holdings Limited22 Honeysuckle DriveNewcastle NSW 2300AUSTRALIAPhone: 13 14 63 (within Australia)+61 2 4914 1100 (outside Australia)Attention: Group Privacy OfficerYou can also contact your local nib entity. We will respond to your request for accessto personal information we hold about you within the timeframes required by applicablelaws and/or as soon as we reasonably can, including notifying you if we are unable to

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 12 of 13

provide access (such as when we no longer hold the information) or if we are permittedby applicable law to refuse access.Generally, we do not impose any charge for a request for access, but where permittedto do so by applicable law, we may charge you a reasonable fee for the retrieval costsassociated with providing you with access.You must keep us informed of any changes to your information, like your contactdetails or address, to ensure your details remain up-to-date.For complaints about privacy, we will establish in consultation with you a reasonableprocess for seeking to resolve your complaint, including time frames provided byapplicable laws.

5.2.European Economic Area (EEA) and United Kingdom

If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA) and require furtherinformation about how we deal with your personal data under EEA data protectionlaws, please contact us at:nib Travel Services Ireland Limited / nib Travel Services Europe LimitedCity Quarter BuildingLapps Quay, Cork, IRELAND.PrivacyEU@nibtravel.comUnder EU laws, additional rights may also be available to you about the way we handleyour personal data, including the right to complain to your local supervisory authority:Data Protection Commission21 Fitzwilliam SquareSouth Dublin 2 D02RD28 IRELAND

www.dataprotection.iedpo@dataprotection.ie

If you are located in the United Kingdom and are not satisfied with our or your insurer’sresponse, or believe we or your insurer are not processing data in accordance with thelaw, you can complain to your local Data Protection Commissioner:Information Commissioners OfficeWycliffe HouseWater LaneWilmslowCheshireSK9 5AFOther rights which may be available to you under UK and EU laws include:a) right to access your personal data (you have the right to request a copy of yourpersonal data that we hold about you, and please see further above);b) right to rectification (as noted, if you believe that the information we hold about youis inaccurate or incomplete, please let us know so that we can rectify any gap orinaccuracy);c) right to erasure, or right to be forgotten (in certain circumstances, you have theright to request that we erase your personal data, such as if your personal data isno longer necessary for the purpose of original collection);d) right to restriction of processing (in certain circumstances, you have the right torequest that we restrict the processing of your personal data, and please seefurther above for example in relation to how you may opt out of ourmarketing communications);e) right to data portability (in certain circumstances, you can request that personal

Privacy Policy Last approved July 2024 Page 13 of 13

data we hold about you be transmitted directly to another organisation);f) right to object (you may have the right to object to our processing of your personaldata, such as in relation to direct marketing communications and your right to optout as outlined above, or to otherwise object unless we establish that we havelegitimate grounds for the processing which outweighs your privacy rights); andg) rights relating to automated decision making (you have the right to ask us to not tobe subject to a decision based solely on automated processing including profilingwhich produces legal effects or other similar significant effects concerning you).

5.3.nib Securities

If you hold nib securities, we have outsourced nib holdings lLmited’s share registryfunction to Computershare Investor Services Pty Limited, which has its own privacypolicy. For more information about how Computershare deals with personalinformation, or to make a complaint about Computershare’s handling of your personalinformation in your capacity as a security holder, please refer to its privacy policy atwww.computershare.com/au or by contacting Computershare (telephone: 1800 804985, or by email privacy@computershare.com.au).

Last updated: July 2024
